<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/page.xsl" ?>

<page xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <xi:include href="common/common.xml#xpointer(//*)" />

  <title>OMiSCID Documentation Page</title>
  <currentMenu id="Documentation"/>

  <content>
    <h1>Installation</h1>
    
    <h2>General Information</h2>
      <p>The current version of <omiscid/> requires DNSSD to be installed and running. For example, you can use mDNSResponder (Bonjour from Apple).</p>
    <h2>C++</h2>
      <p>In order to compile your <omiscid/> source code, you will need to have Bonjour, libxml with their C++ headers and libs for bindings.</p>
    <h2>Java</h2>
      <p>The Java version of <omiscid/> requires a DNSSD implementation to be installed. For example, you will need to install mDNSResponder (Apple Bonjour) together with its Java bindings. See the OSGi tutorial for more details about this installation.</p>
      <p>The developement using the non-OSGi version of omiscid just requires to have the following jars in your classpath:
        <ul>
          <li>omiscid.jar: the omiscid library</li>
          <li>xerces-J_1.4.0.jar, commons-logging.jar, castor-1.0.1-xml.jar, log4j-1.2.8.jar: the base libraries required by <a href="http://www.castor.org/xml-framework.html">Castor XML</a></li>
          <li>jakarta-oro-2.0.8.jar: the <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/oro/">apache jakarta oro library</a> required by some Castor XML features</li>
        </ul>
        Note that all the dependencies to Castor will probably be replaced when Java 6 will be released and widely available.
      </p>
      <p>You can access the <a href="download/doc-java/javadoc/index.html">javadoc of the user centered API</a> on this website.</p>
    <h2>OSGi</h2>
    
    <h1>Tutorials</h1>
    <h2>C++</h2>
      <p>You can use the following resources in order to train yourself using <omiscid/>:
         <ul>
           <li>the under-development version of the  <a href="download/doc-c++/Doc/index.html">doxygen documentation</a></li>
           <li>a <a href="download/doc-c++/OMiSCID-C++Tutorial.pdf">tutorial</a> about using user-friendly interface to build  <omiscid/> services.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    <h2>Java</h2>
      <p>As the C++ and Java APIs are almost identical (modulo the languages specifity), you can probably take the C++ tutorials as a basis. Your favorite IDE will probably allow you to cope with the slight differences between the C++ and Java APIs.</p>
    <h2>OSGi</h2>
    
    <h1>Publications</h1>
    <p>For a detailled description of <omiscid/> architecture and design goals, see this <a href="http://www-prima.inrialpes.fr/prima/pub/Publications/2006/EVRL06/">paper presented at the IEEE workshop SIPE-2006</a>.</p>
  </content>

</page>